<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>github on Ben Selby</title>
    <link>https://benmatselby.dev/tags/github/</link>
    <description>Recent content in github on Ben Selby</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 09:19:38 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://benmatselby.dev/tags/github/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Comparison: AWS CodePipeline, GitHub Actions, and Jenkins</title>
      <link>https://benmatselby.dev/post/build-tool-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 09:19:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benmatselby.dev/post/build-tool-comparison/</guid>
      <description>This post has come about as I&amp;rsquo;ve written up this content in different formats multiple times, and it&amp;rsquo;s easier to write this up once, and just reference back.
The tools this post is going to compare are:
 AWS CodePipeline (As I happen to be working in the AWS space at the moment) Jenkins GitHub Actions  A couple of things to note:
 This post almost exclusively talks about AWS CodePipeline, but you will almost certainly require AWS CodeBuild too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gollum Page Watcher GitHub Action</title>
      <link>https://benmatselby.dev/post/gollum-page-watcher-github-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 18:39:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benmatselby.dev/post/gollum-page-watcher-github-action/</guid>
      <description>Finding out when code changes in your project is easy. Whether it is version control, build notifications, GitHub/GitLab notifications, there are many delivery mechanisms to notify you.
But what about all that documentation you spend a lot of time on. Curating your system, tweaking guidelines, and examples. How do you get teams of engineers to know about changes?
There isn&amp;rsquo;t that many options in this space.
If you are a Slack user, and if you use GitHub as your documentation/wiki space, then the Gollum Page Watcher can help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Deploy GitHub Action</title>
      <link>https://benmatselby.dev/post/hugo-deploy-github-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 20:31:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benmatselby.dev/post/hugo-deploy-github-action/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just released version v1.2.1 of the Hugo Deploy to GitHub Pages GitHub Action.
This means it now fully conforms to the metadata specification as defined here.
I wrote this action back when GitHub Actions were still in beta, and there were very few actions out there. It turns out there are a plethora of GitHub Actions to now deploy a Hugo site to GitHub Pages, but where is the fun in using someone else&amp;rsquo;s?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
