<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vscode on Ben Selby</title>
    <link>https://benmatselby.dev/tags/vscode/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vscode on Ben Selby</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 14:35:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://benmatselby.dev/tags/vscode/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Debugging Python with a virtual environment in VSCode</title>
      <link>https://benmatselby.dev/post/debugging-python-with-env-vscode/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 14:35:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://benmatselby.dev/post/debugging-python-with-env-vscode/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My current job is mainly Python, so there was a steep learning curve. I have done some Python previously, but mainly for writing &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/benmatselby/sublime-phpcs&#34;&gt;Sublime&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/benmatselby/sublime-jenkins-dashboard&#34;&gt;Text&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/benmatselby/sublime-phpdocumentor&#34;&gt;plugins&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/benmatselby/sublime-pman&#34;&gt;back in the day&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over the last few months, I’ve set up my VSCode environment on my work machine. Last night I was wanting to do something on a different machine. I could not remember how to debug Python code inside a virtual environment within VSCode!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I kept getting this error&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a VS Code Dev Container - minikube</title>
      <link>https://benmatselby.dev/post/vscode-dev-containers-minikube/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 11:44:20 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://benmatselby.dev/post/vscode-dev-containers-minikube/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post builds on what we already learnt in &lt;a href=&#34;https://benmatselby.dev/post/vscode-dev-containers/&#34;&gt;Setting up a VS Code Dev Container&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s more specific goal is to discuss running Dev Containers whilst using &lt;a href=&#34;https://minikube.sigs.k8s.io/docs/&#34;&gt;minikube&lt;/a&gt; as a Docker Desktop replacement on the Mac.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is lots of chatter about the new license for Docker Desktop. The license changes impacts the business I work for. I wanted to know what our options were.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Getting minikube as a drop in replacement for Docker Desktop on the Mac, was relatively straight forward.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a VS Code Dev Container</title>
      <link>https://benmatselby.dev/post/vscode-dev-containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 09:15:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://benmatselby.dev/post/vscode-dev-containers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week my team was tasked with picking up a project that I had last worked on 4 years ago. The deadline was tight, and we had a week to complete it. It was written in PHP, a language I&amp;rsquo;d barely written in the last 3 years. Obviously a lot has changed in 4 years (both in the language, setup, and the team I work in). I am the only engineer in my team now who knows PHP.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
