<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Communication on Ben Selby</title>
    <link>https://benmatselby.dev/tags/communication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Communication on Ben Selby</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 18:39:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://benmatselby.dev/tags/communication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Show your working out</title>
      <link>https://benmatselby.dev/post/2024/show-your-working-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 18:39:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://benmatselby.dev/post/2024/show-your-working-out/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Does anyone remember what your Maths teacher used to say?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Show your working out!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I mean, I bet they said more than that, but this is what I remembered. I think we used to get marked down if you just provided the answer. You got more marks when you showed how you derived your answer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This post is a plea for software engineers to do the same when answering technical questions, or debugging an issue in group communication channels.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Naming Slack huddles</title>
      <link>https://benmatselby.dev/post/2023/naming-slack-huddles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 21:28:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://benmatselby.dev/post/2023/naming-slack-huddles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m pair programming more and more nowadays. One thing that features heavily in pair programming is a Slack huddle. My main recommendation is to &lt;strong&gt;name the Slack huddle&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Slack is a very useful tool to use when pair programming. For me, it&amp;rsquo;s simply the ability to draw on each others screen. Trying to describe the many buttons, areas of an IDE, or where to change a line of code is painful. Being able to draw on the screen is not.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Team communication tools</title>
      <link>https://benmatselby.dev/post/communication-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 07:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://benmatselby.dev/post/communication-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&#34;https://benmatselby.dev/post/communication/&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt; I talked about communication, and what it’s like as a remote engineer. I also hinted at the tooling I prefer, and outlined what I look for. This post is going to cover off why I prefer &lt;a href=&#34;https://slack.com&#34;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; for team chat/communication.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Spanning a 10 year period I’ve used: IRC, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apache_Wave&#34;&gt;Google Wave&lt;/a&gt;, XMPP in various forms, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.skype.com/en/&#34;&gt;Skype&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://hangouts.google.com&#34;&gt;GTalk and Google Hangouts&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://slack.com&#34;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/education/products/teams/default.aspx&#34;&gt;Microsoft Teams&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en-gb.facebook.com/workplace&#34;&gt;Workplace&lt;/a&gt;. Slack is a clear winner for me, although at the time Google Wave blew me away.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Communication</title>
      <link>https://benmatselby.dev/post/communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 12:08:10 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://benmatselby.dev/post/communication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s cliched to say, but communication really is key, and yet it’s one of the common issues folks seem to raise in departmental or company feedback. “Communication isn’t great”. However, this is both a top down, and a bottom up issue in my opinion (and everything in between).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Top down like to send out update emails, but the flow of communication is one way. Do I reply, reply all, face to face? Engagement here is not great.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
