<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>git on Ben Selby</title>
    <link>https://benmatselby.dev/tags/git/</link>
    <description>Recent content in git on Ben Selby</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 21:31:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://benmatselby.dev/tags/git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Git commands to get you through the day</title>
      <link>https://benmatselby.dev/post/git-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 21:31:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benmatselby.dev/post/git-101/</guid>
      <description>Since the start of the year, I&amp;rsquo;ve been running weekly workshops with Paddy Morgan at work. These have been fun sessions to run. Some have been chats, some demos etc.
However, this week we ran a &amp;ldquo;Git 101&amp;rdquo; workshop. Weirdly, this was the most attended workshop we have run, with around 50 engineers joining throughout the hour session.
This post covers what we ran through.
 Time allocation: 60 minutes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logically atomic commits</title>
      <link>https://benmatselby.dev/post/logical-commits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 10:21:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benmatselby.dev/post/logical-commits/</guid>
      <description>When forming a new team (or joining a team for that matter), I always try to get the following item in our code review standards, or ways of working.
Make sure all commits in version control are logically atomic.  What is a logically atomic commit A logically atomic commit is the smallest, most meaningful change you can make to the software. It&amp;rsquo;s big enough to add value, but small enough to be manageable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Squashing commits</title>
      <link>https://benmatselby.dev/post/squashing-commits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 07:23:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benmatselby.dev/post/squashing-commits/</guid>
      <description>I recently got involved in a project where I contributed a patch to an inflight feature branch. I then raised a Pull Request into the feature branch, so I could annotate the code in the GitHub PR to explain why I had done it a certain way. After a bit of back and forth the PR was merged into the feature branch.
Later, I found that the feature branch I had worked on had been merged into master, but the entire branch was squashed down into one commit.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
