<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes on Ben Selby</title>
    <link>https://benmatselby.dev/tags/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notes on Ben Selby</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 09:36:28 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://benmatselby.dev/tags/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Running Ubuntu on a MacBook Pro</title>
      <link>https://benmatselby.dev/post/2024/ubuntu-with-mac-keyboard-combo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 09:36:28 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://benmatselby.dev/post/2024/ubuntu-with-mac-keyboard-combo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note: This post is a work in progress, and mainly for my notes. It&amp;rsquo;s current as of May 2024!&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had a ten year old MacBook Pro lying around not really doing anything. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t doing very well with the macOS either, so decided to run Ubuntu on it. Ubuntu was my main development environment from about 2008 until about 2011, and I miss it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, as a life long Mac user, the keyboard shortcuts and combinations are too much muscle memory for me to try and move away from. Also, this is a fun side project. I&amp;rsquo;m not entirely moving over to Ubuntu, so I don&amp;rsquo;t really want to change my muscle memory too much.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-cursor support in Obsidian</title>
      <link>https://benmatselby.dev/post/obsidian-multi-cursor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 13:18:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://benmatselby.dev/post/obsidian-multi-cursor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post brings together two of my favourite things: Note taking, and multiple cursors. I remember the first time an engineer introduced me to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sublimetext.com&#34;&gt;Sublime Text&lt;/a&gt;. The main thing he would bang on about was multiple cursors. I was very quickly sold. It&amp;rsquo;s pure magic and speeds up so many things. I instantly switched from Eclipse PDT to Sublime Text.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always liked writing notes, but always struggled with various tools. I have a work diary going back to 2009! I&amp;rsquo;ve used &lt;code&gt;vim&lt;/code&gt;, VSCode, Sublime Text, but they never really got it right. I have even tried hand writing notes in journals, it&amp;rsquo;s not for me, no matter how much I want it to be!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
